there are numerous ways that a function
might fail to be differentiable at a
point you might have a removable
discontinuity or a so-called hole at the
point similarly you might have a jump
discontinuity in this case it's
impossible to have a uniquely defined
tangent line in fact any discontinuity
leads to a point of
non-differentiability so vertical ASM
tootes also create problems such as the
one you might find in the function 1 /x
like this you might also have a point
where there's an Abrupt change in slope
this is often called a cusp or a corner
and it appears in functions like the
absolute value function another way is
that you might have a vertical tangent
line like the one appearing in the cube
root function this would correspond to
an infinite slope which is undefined so
we've seen that discontinuities places
with abrupt changes in slope and points
where there is a vertical tangent line
all create problems for
differentiability can you think of any
other situations where a function won't
be differentiable